<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Notes</title><id>https://carnotweat.github.io/feed.xml</id><subtitle>Recent Posts</subtitle><updated>2023-11-06T09:09:47Z</updated><link href="carnotweat.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" /><link href="carnotweat.github.io" /><entry><title>nix!</title><id>https://carnotweat.github.io/nix.html</id><author><name>Sameer Gupta</name><email>jasitis@gmail.com</email></author><updated>2023-11-06T18:00:00Z</updated><link href="https://carnotweat.github.io/nix.html" rel="alternate" /><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;ATM I just added this to check haunt builds with skribe and some tweaks to deploy.I ll later
detail my notes here on flakes,shell,overlay, skribe, guix, mostly with a page besides github,
with podman,emacs,nix-deploy, as good as it gets. Atm i build in main and deploy with gh-pages.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>About!</title><id>https://carnotweat.github.io/about.html</id><author><name>Sameer Gupta</name><email>jasitis@gmail.com</email></author><updated>2023-11-06T18:00:00Z</updated><link href="https://carnotweat.github.io/about.html" rel="alternate" /><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Recently, I could focus and  ve made some progress in managing my auth secrets, gpg and automating
some git with this together with bash and nix, with emacs as $EDITOR, thanks to flake and
home-manager.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In process of adding a guix overlay to to my nix config, as I needed guile[^1] to use haunt for
this place along with forgefed (activitypub based git forge) and the I can abandon this place.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the same time I am putting a nix flake together to stabelize my orgmode (finally)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thats my flow with tools, I don't put time because I know something, but when it's useful in
everyday desk issues, which changes and  do the tools..&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I learnt this from market (not a rosy experience), they appreciate the good , but invest in purpose.
Exception to this are&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Curry paradox and Curry Howard Isomorphism&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The latter gives an equivalance between something stationary (proof) and something dynamic
(program).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;It questions the relational model of motion, like newton's rotating bucket paradox does and
binds the work of programming to the pursuit of logic and pure math&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Nix is an interesting juncture tooling for tooling friction in actually doing it, theory, takes
time and effort&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;So This an interesting meta-inflection point in this context of my long term note taking and
referencing habit on interent
[^1]: while orgmode is way more maximalist and simpler than a doc programming framework, skribolo
markup is closer to scheme and I plan to use it along with markdown, guile is in nixpkgs , guix is
not. Besides, I came across the work of Xi Iaso-nix, Andre van Meulebrouck's conversion from Scheme
to Haskell, which sets the direction for now.Org is notorious for breaking with versions, but that
is something nix can look after&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry></feed>